Do you and the Dachi High team wanna
come over and train with us this weekend?
（柴木山(しばきやま)）
今週末 ダチ高のみんなで
ウチに出稽古に来ないか？
Sumo wrestlers from another stable are
joining us for a joint training session.
ほかの部屋の力士たちも交えて
合同稽古をするんだけど
You'll get the chance to fight
a current ozeki wrestler.
そこで 現役大関と
相撲を取らせてあげよう
A-An ozeki?!
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）お… 大関！？
The Dachi High sumo club
ダチ高相撲部 名古屋(なごや)に上陸じゃ！
has arrived in Nagoya!
Miso cutlets and chicken wings!
（千比路(ちひろ)）
味噌(みそ)カツ 手羽先　ウオ〜ッ！
（桐仁(きりひと)）
こらこら　遊びに来てんじゃねえぞ
Hey, now. We're not here as tourists.
We're here to train, remember.
目的は あくまで稽古だ 稽古
We got here quicker than I thought.
（佑真(ゆうま)）思ったより早く着いたな
The master's got a meeting, so we
won't see him till this evening, right?
親方は会合で
夕方まで会えねえんだろう？
じゃ 時間までミーティングだな
Yeah, so we'll have our own
team meeting until then.
はぁ？　ウソだろう
せっかく名古屋まで来たんだぜ
You've gotta be kidding!
We've come all the way to Nagoya, dude!
He's got a point.
（小関(おぜき)）そうだよな
ミーティングは夜でも十分できるし
We can have a team meeting tonight.
I want to go see Nagoya Castle.
（蛍(けい)）名古屋城も見たいですし
Oh, honestly.
おいおい　…たく
Tell them, Hinomaru.
火ノ丸からも
何とか言ってやってくれ
Nagoya Castle sounds great.
（火ノ丸）名古屋城 いいのぅ
（桐仁）ええっ？
Wh-What do you say, Kirihito?
ど… どうじゃろう？　桐仁
ちょっと見るくらいなら…
A quick detour won't hurt.
I'm not used to Ushio
saying things like that.
（小関）潮(うしお)が そういうこと言うの
なんか珍しいな
ふだんはストイックの権化なのに
He's normally the dictionary
definition of stoicism.
Well, training for the national
tournament will undoubtedly be tense.
まあ 実際 全国大会への稽古で
気を張り詰め通しなのも確かだ
This may be their only chance
to catch their breath
今を逃したら ひと息つく機会も
名古屋では もうねえからな
before we leave Nagoya.
Okay, let's go check out Nagoya Castle.
（桐仁）
分かったよ　行くか 名古屋城
Yeah!
Huh? Where'd the others go?
（蛍）あれ？　ほかのみんなは？
（千比路）ハ〜ッ！　城なんか
毛ほども興味ねえよ　メシだ！
Castles don't interest me one little bit.
Let's eat!
My sentiments exactly.
（佑真）俺も こっちだ
I want to try some Nagoya cuisine.
（小関）
名古屋メシ 食べてみたいな
Bout 12
"Attack!! Nagoya Castle"
Welcome
Suzugatake Faction
High school sumo?
（親方Ａ）高校相撲？
Oh, you mean those national treasures
sumo fans are always going on about.
（親方Ａ）ああ…　国宝だ何だと
相撲ファンが騒いどるやつか
It's a bumper crop this year. The kind
that only comes around once a century.
（親方Ｂ）今年はホントに—
100年に１度あるかないかの
大豊作だよ
Still, this year's high school yokozuna
is bound to be Tennoji-kun again.
（親方Ｃ）…とはいえ 今年も
高校横綱は天王寺(てんのうじ)君で決まりだろう
Tennoji's good, but there's also
Yamatokuni's boy, Kuze Sosuke.
（親方Ｄ）天王寺もよいが—
目玉は何といっても
大和国(やまとくに)の息子 久世草介(くぜそうすけ)
I think he's got what it takes to earn
himself a national treasure moniker.
彼こそ 国宝と呼ぶに
ふさわしい逸材だと思うね
One or two stand-out fighters
does not a bumper crop make.
（柴木山）
１人や２人ずぬけたぐらいで
大豊作とはいわんでしょう
This year's high school sumo has been like
the Sengoku era, with several great talents.
（柴木山）今年の高校相撲は
正に群雄割拠の戦国時代ってやつだ
ウヘヘッ…　楽しいのぅ！
This is fun!
みんな メシなんか あとにして
来りゃよかったのに
I wish the others had left stuffing their
faces till later and come with us instead!
I don't really get what's fun about it,
but I'm glad you're having a good time.
よく分からんが
お前が楽しいなら いいよ
つうか 名古屋城って 誰の城？
宮本武蔵(みやもとむさし)？
By the way, who built Nagoya Castle?
Miyamoto Musashi?
History's not my bag,
and even I know you're way off.
（蛍）僕は 歴史あんまりですけど
その答えは さすがに引きますね
Nagoya Castle was constructed
by Tokugawa Ieyasu
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）名古屋城を築城したのは
徳川家康(とくがわいえやす)ですよね
for his ninth son, Yoshinao.
９男 義直(よしなお)のために
Good knowledge, Hori-chan!
オッ！　やるな 堀(ほり)ちゃん
義直は実直な感じが 結構 好きじゃ
I always liked Yoshinao for his honesty.
What are you two, history buffs?
（桐仁）
なんだ お前ら　歴史マニアか？
（慶次(けいじ)）さあ！
寄ってらっしゃい 見てらっしゃい
Come one, come all!
The Sengoku period's
greatest hoodlum stands here!
この前田(まえだ)慶次と相撲を
取りたいヤツは いねえかい？
Does anyone dare to challenge
Maeda Keiji to a sumo bout?
I do! I do! Sumo with Keiji! Sumo with Keiji!
はいはいは〜い！
慶次と相撲　慶次と相撲！
おい　いいけど やりすぎるなよ
相手は役者さんなんだから
Hey! You can fight, but don't overdo it.
He's just an actor, after all.
（慶次）
オッ…　やけに元気なヤツがいるね
This guy looks pretty eager.
（慶次）じゃ そこの…
（典馬(てんま)）はい
Okay, let's...
Yeah.
あっ…　いやいや
慶次はワシを指したんじゃぞ
No, dude, Keiji was pointing at me.
先に手を挙げたのもワシじゃし
I raised my hand first, too.
（典馬）はぁ？
慶次が誰とやりたいかでしょう
Huh? Surely it's up to Keiji who he fights.
And he and I just made eye contact.
俺 慶次と バッチリ目ぇ合ったし
Hey, give me a break!
（火ノ丸）
おいおい　勘弁しとくれ！
ワシは
千葉から はるばる来たんじゃ
I've come all the way from Chiba to be here!
So what? I've come from Ishikawa.
（典馬）それが何だっての？
こっちは石川県だよ
前田家っつったら石川県でしょう
君は おとなしく千葉に帰って—
The Maeda family was from Ishikawa, too.
Just go back to Chiba and wrestle
some guy in a mouse costume there.
ネズミの着ぐるみとでも
相撲取ってろよ
なに！？
歴史好きとして引き下がれるか！
What'd you say?!
As a history enthusiast, I refuse!
And Keiji was from Yamagata!
あと 慶次は
どっちかというと山形県じゃろう！
（典馬）…ていうかさ
君 そもそも そんなナリで—
All that aside, do you really think
you'd be a match for Keiji?
慶次に勝てると思うの？
I don't like people underestimating Keiji,
慶次のことナメてるのも
ムカつくけど—
相撲ナメられるのは
もっとムカつく
but I like people
underestimating sumo even less.
H-He's huge!
（蛍）で… でかっ！
And that's going to
seriously piss off Hinomaru...
（桐仁）
…つうか それ 火ノ丸には禁句
ああ？　誰が相撲をナメてるって？
And who are you suggesting
is "underestimating" sumo?
You are, kid. You.
君だよ 君　ほかにいないでしょう
Who else would I mean?
ウヘヘッ…　そこまで言うなら
相撲で決めようか
If that's how you feel, let's have
a bout to settle our argument.
One to decide who should
get the chance to take on Keiji.
どっちが
慶次の相手に ふさわしいかをな
俺は別にいいけど
どうなっても知らないよ
Fine by me, but I won't be held
responsible if you end up getting hurt.
なんだか
妙なことになっちゃったけど—
Well, this is an unexpected development...
But it sounds like fun, so go right ahead!
面白そうだから
やっちゃって 君たち！
He was supposed to be taking a breather,
but he's ended up sumo wrestling, anyway.
（千鶴子）息抜きのはずが
結局 相撲なんですね
Please... Don't anybody get hurt.
頼むから
２人ともケガだけは すんなよ
Okay, let's see what you got!
さあ！　見合って 見合って
This guy...
こいつ…
（親方Ａ）戦国時代か
The Sengoku era, huh?
You all do seem to be neglecting
another very important name.
確かに皆さんは 大事なヤツを１人
忘れているようだ
Ah, yes. When talking about promising high
school students, we can't overlook him.
（親方Ｃ）ああ 確かに
期待の高校生といえば—
彼も忘れてはいけない
Yeah, I was thinking of inviting
him to our little training session.
（親方Ａ）
そう　実は その彼も—
例の稽古に
参加させようと思っている
"Him"?
“彼”？
Spirit!
はっきよい！
He's the strongest of the lot and
the closest to becoming a yokozuna.
今 最も横綱に近い最強力士
He's the younger brother
of the ozeki, Daikeisho.
大関 大景勝(だいけいしょう)…　その弟だよ
He pushed Hinomaru-san
to the edge with one hit?
（蛍）火ノ丸さんが１発で土俵際！
What? How's this happening
here of all places?
（桐仁）
そんな…　なんで こんな所に…
I thought that'd be enough to finish you.
（典馬）終わらせる気で
打ったんだけどな　やるじゃん
You're not bad.
What a terrifying strike.
なんて突きじゃ　まともに
食らったら 首が吹っ飛ぶぞ！
If I get hit by that,
it'll knock my head clean off!
Unleashing powerful strikes
with a massive reach...
（桐仁）圧倒的なリーチから
繰り出される強烈な突きは—
Reputed to be the best high school sumo,
with an ozeki for an older brother...
高校一ともいわれ
現役大関を兄に持つ—
National treasure: Odenta Mitsuyo,
AKA Hikage Tenma!
国宝 大典太光世(おおでんたみつよ)　日景(ひかげ)典馬！
That's enough, Hinomaru!
もういい　火ノ丸！　こんな所で
お前の力を見せる必要はねえ！
There's no need to show your strength here!
No, it's the exact opposite!
違う！　逆じゃろう！
見せるんじゃねえ
こいつの力を見るんじゃ！
I'm not showing him mine.
I'm gonna see what he's got!
It's not just Tennoji and Kuze
I need to defeat.
倒すべきは
天王寺や久世だけじゃねえんだ
ワシの力が
全国で どれほどのものか…
I need to see how far my strength
will take me at nationals!
And you're going to be
the measuring stick, Odenta!
てめえで測らせてもらうぜ
大典太！
A frontal grab!
（蛍）前褌(まえみつ)！　いけー！
Go!
Take this! Maximum strength for nationals!
食らえ 全国　ワシの全力！
百千夜叉(ひゃくせんやしゃ)…
Hundred-Thousand Demon...
何じゃ？　このイヤな感じは
What's this sinking feeling?
Come to think of it, why'd he
let me grab him so easily?
そもそも こんな簡単に
廻(まわ)しを取らせてくれる相手か？
If I continue with this throw, will I lose?
もし このまま投げに入れば
ワシは 負け…
What's wrong? Show me your throw...
（典馬）どうした？
早く例の投げを見せてくれよ 鬼丸(おにまる)
Onimaru.
（米村(よねむら)）おらぁ！
I've been looking all over
for you, Tenma, you dolt!
（米村）
捜したぞ てめえ こら 典馬！
You've got some nerve, competing in a bout
when you're meant to be cleaning the hall.
（米村）合宿所の掃除サボって
相撲とは いい身分だな
You may be a national treasure,
but don't let it get to your head!
国宝だ何だ
調子乗ってんじゃねえぞ！
（典馬）はぁ？
全然 調子乗ってないんですけど
But I haven't.
自分の持ち場は ちゃんとやったし
I already did my bit.
（米村）キャプテン
Captain!
Can you please tell him?
It's impossible to get through to him.
言ってやってくださいよ
この人 話 通じなくて
It looks like our club member
has been causing you trouble.
（相沢(あいざわ)）いやぁ ウチの部員が—
迷惑かけたみたいで
どうも すみません
Please accept our apologies.
勝負の途中だったみたいだけど
今日は この辺で失礼します
I realize you were in the middle of a bout,
but we must excuse ourselves.
You can finish your fight at nationals,
（相沢）続きは全国大会でやろうね
三点投げの鬼丸君
Mr. Triple Combo, Onimaru-kun.
（蛍）ハッ…　今 何て？
What did he just say?
He made it sound like
they're looking out for it.
警戒してますって言い方じゃねえか
Hikage's stance was
clearly inviting a throw.
（桐仁）日景の動きは
明らかに投げを誘ってた
It's been less than a week
since the Inter High.
インターハイ予選から
まだ１週間足らずだぞ
Do they already know how to counter it?
もう何かしらの対策を？
So how did you like meeting
Onimaru-kun in the flesh?
…で どうだったの？　鬼丸君は
映像と比べて
思ったより臆病だったね
He was more of a coward than I expected.
まあ しかたないか
自分の技が死ぬのは見たくないよね
Can't blame him, though.
No one wants to see their own
technique get utterly destroyed.
S
h
i
b
a
k
i
y
a
m
Stable
S
a
e
n
o
y
a
m
-
z
e
k
i
（小関）ウワッ！　くそ！
（寺原(てらはら)）ハハハッ…
Damn!
We can't let you high schoolers
beat us that easily.
高校生相手に
そう やすやすと負けてらんねえぜ
Thank you for your hard work!
（力士たち）
お疲れさんでございます
（冴ノ山(さえのやま)）潮君
（火ノ丸）あっ…
Ushio-kun.
Um, where are we going, Saenoyama-zeki?
（火ノ丸）
あの…　冴ノ山関　どこへ？
You look dejected.
（冴ノ山）気の抜けた顔ですね
（火ノ丸）あっ…
I heard you've hit another wall.
（冴ノ山）
また壁に ぶつかっているそうで
（火ノ丸）大丈夫です
It'll be okay.
But it seems my best weapon
won't bail me out at nationals.
ただ ワシの最大の武器が
どうやら 全国では通用しない
Honestly, it's getting to me a little.
それは正直 こたえています
What are you talking about?
何言ってんですか
Your greatest weapon is
your heart that refuses to give up.
君の最大の武器は
くじけぬ心でしょう
That master called you all the way out here
（冴ノ山）親方が君を
ここへ呼んだということは—
must mean he believes something here
will help you smash through that wall.
ここに その壁を越えるための
何かがあるはずです
And that's the Suzugatake Faction,
which the Shibakiyama Stable is part of.
柴木山部屋を含めた鈴ヶ嶽(すずがたけ)一門
その中でも—
It represents what
you always desire the most:
君が いつも欲しがっている—
an ordeal that'll make you stronger.
強くなれる地獄ですよ
We can see the whole
sumo ring from here.
（千鶴子）ここなら
土俵全体が見えますよね
Let's set up here.
ここにしましょう
Y-Yeah...
（礼奈(れいな)）う… うん
But aren't we filming them
without permission?
（礼奈）ねえ　これって盗撮だよね
（千鶴子）監督の指示ですから
The instructor told us to.
あの２人のあとをつけて
稽古の様子を撮ってきてくれ
Follow those two and film their training.
But why are just those two
training separately?
でも なんで あの２人だけ別なの？
Do only a select few
get invited into that tent?
ここは選ばれし者しか
入れない的な？
Yes, everyone in there
has a white mawashi belt.
（千鶴子）
はい　ここにいるのは全員 白廻し
つまり 関取です
Meaning they're all sekitori.
Sekitori are sumo wrestlers
in the juryo rank and above.
関取っていうのは—
番付が十両以上の
プロの中でも上位の限られた存在
They're considered the elite,
even among the pros.
H-How do you know so much?
な… なんで そんなに詳しいのよ？
相撲に興味持ったのは最近だって…
You only just got into sumo...
I did some research after joining the club.
入部を決めてから勉強したんです
I'm their manager, so I need
to be as useful as possible.
マネージャーになったからには
役に立ちたいですから
Thank you for your hard work!
お疲れさんでございます！
So you're the national treasure?
（三尾錦(みおにしき)）君が国宝君か
柴木山さんのお気に入りの
The one Shibakiyama-san likes.
I'm Ushio Hinomaru!
潮火ノ丸です！
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for having me!
Stow the gratitude.
What are you doing here?
いや…
よろしくも何も 何しに来たの？
（三尾錦）名古屋場所を
目前に控えた この大事な時期にさ
This is a critical time for us in the
run-up to the Nagoya Tournament.
We're all here to get
some quality training done.
質の高い稽古をするために
わざわざ集まったってのに—
What's an amateur doing in here?
なんで こんな素人を…
Well, I didn't agree to this, either.
（関取Ａ）まあ…
俺だって納得はしてないッスよ
（火ノ丸）ンッ…
（三尾錦）大相撲は番付が全てだ
Rank is everything in professional sumo.
Promising high schooler prospect or not,
期待の高校生だろうが—
nobody gets to boss around
wrestlers of higher rank.
番付が上の者に対して
我を通す権利はない
You don't even have a rank. You're nothing
more than a worm in our presence.
番付にすら載らない君は
ここでは虫けらも同然なんだよ
まあ 歓迎はされんだろうね
Well, I doubt they'll be the most welcoming.
えっ？　話は通してあるんじゃ…
You didn't get their approval?
Sekitori are a proud bunch.
（柴木山）関取ってのは
我の強い連中ばかりさ
They got to where they are
by fighting for it.
腕っぷしひとつで
そこまで上り詰めたんだ
Those without pride
could never make it there.
そうでなくては務まらん
The sumo ring is sacred ground where only
the rank of the current wrestlers matters.
土俵は 番付というルールが
支配する現役だけの聖域
I can lead him to the straw of
the ring, but not one step farther.
僕とて連れていけるのは
土俵の俵１コ外までだ
Whether he can get inside
and grasp something
その中へ入れば 何かつかめるか…
depends on Hinomaru-kun's determination.
それこそ
火ノ丸君の“我”しだいだよ
What do you say, Sae?
Not gonna bail him out?
（三尾錦）
いいのか？　冴　放っておいて
助け船でも出してやれよ
No, I won't.
（冴ノ山）
出しませんよ そんなもの
I have brought a bona fide
sumo wrestler to the ring.
私は ひとりの力士を
ここへ連れてきたんですから
If you consider me an eyesore,
feel free to push me out of the ring.
ワシが目障りじゃと思うなら
力ずくで追い出せばいい
Rank is everything...
番付が全て…　要は ワシに—
I just need to be strong enough to
be a good training partner, right?
皆さんの稽古相手が務まるだけの
実力があればいいんでしょう
Please decide my rank right here and now.
なら 決めてくださいよ
今ここで ワシの番付を
What's he thinking?
なに考えてんのよ
相手は強いんでしょう？
That guy's really strong, isn't he?
はい　東前頭(ひがしまえがしら)八枚目 三尾錦関
Yes. He's the eighth-ranked east
maegashita, Mionishiki-seki.
He's a higher rank than Saenoyama-zeki.
番付上は 冴ノ山関より上です
But that means...
それって…
Ushio-kun has never beaten Saenoyama-zeki.
潮君は 冴ノ山関にも
一度も勝ったことがないようです
An eighth-ranked maegashira...
Can I beat him?
前頭八枚目　ワシに勝ち目は…
No, I need to give it all I've got!
いや　全力でやるだけじゃ
出し切らなければ悔いが残る
If I don't, I'll regret it!
もう後悔は したくねえ！
I don't want to taste
any more disappointment!
A spider stance, huh?
（三尾錦）平蜘蛛(ひらぐも)か　こしゃくな…
Impudent child.
Come.
来い
Spirit!
（関取）はっきよい！
（関取Ｂ）オッ…
当たり負けはしたが やるな
He came off second-best,
but he's hanging in there.
In that bout with Hikage,
日景との一戦
なぜ あのとき ワシは—
why did I stop myself mid-move?
自ら 技を止めちまったのか
I was afraid.
ワシは恐れた
Afraid of losing the small amount
I've accomplished up until now.
あいつに負けて 今日まで
積み上げた僅かな実績と—
手応えを失うことを
But...
でも そうじゃねえだろう！
That's not it!
This technique requires you
to put your life on the line!
この技は
命を乗せて放つ技じゃということを
Do not fear death!
死を恐れるな！　踏み込め！
Step forward!
All my body and spirit is going into this!
これが 今のワシの全身全霊！
Hundred-Thousand Demon Drop!
百千夜叉墜(ひゃくせんやしゃおとし)！
What was that?
何だ？　今の技は
（千鶴子）あっ…
（礼奈）よし！
Yes!
ハァ…
It's not dead.
死んでない
百千夜叉墜は まだ死んでない！
The Hundred-Thousand
Demon Drop is still alive!
（冴ノ山）
どうです？　私の弟弟子は
How do you like my junior apprentice?
A tad more useful than
a worm, wouldn't you say?
虫けらと呼ぶには
少しばかり上等でしょう
So that's him.
（駿海(しゅんかい)）
あれか 薫山(かおるやま)のお気に入りってのは
That's the guy Kaoruyama's been on about.
He's one interesting kid.
なかなか奇妙なヤツがいたもんだ
投げた 幕内力士を
I threw a makuuchi sumo wrestler.
That sinking feeling during my bout
with Hikage was all in my head!
日景との一戦で感じた違和感は
心の弱さが招いた気の迷いじゃった
The power of the Hundred-Thousand
Demon Drop is real.
百千夜叉墜の威力は本物じゃ
この技なら 日景だろうが…
I can use this technique against Hikage!
（関取Ｃ）
なるほど　面白い相撲取るな 君
I see! You have a very interesting style.
Would you fight me next?
（関取Ｄ）次 わしと いいかな？
（関取Ｅ）待て待て　次は俺だ
No, wait. I'll go next!
They're all clamoring for his attention now.
さっきとは打って変わって
モテモテじゃん
Was I imagining them all staring at me?
さっきの あの視線は気のせいか？
It looks like he's earned
the right to train here.
（関取）まずは勝ち取ったようだな
ここにいる権利を
Yes, but he's only made it to the start line.
ええ　ですが
まだスタートラインに立っただけ
Welcome to the ordeal.
さあ　地獄にご入場だよ
（関取Ｃ）う〜ん…
際どいが 同体ってことにするか
It was close, but let's say
we hit at the same time.
いや すごい技だ
That's an incredible technique.
Wh-What was that?
な… 何じゃ？　ワシのミスか？
Did I make a mistake?
Okay, I'm next.
（関取Ｄ）よし　次は わしだ
（火ノ丸）あっ…
Spirit!
（関取）はっきよい！
（火ノ丸）ンンッ…
This technique is a triple combo
that there's no coming back from!
この技は ３つの合わせの捨て身技
僅かなズレで死を招く！
If it's not done exactly right, I lose!
（火ノ丸）ウッ！
（関取Ｄ）よいしょ…
There.
フゥ…　こんなものか
I guess that's that.
P-Please wait! Can we go
one more time, please?
ま… 待ってください
もう１回 お願いします！
Sure. We can fight till you're satisfied.
（関取Ｄ）
いいよ 君の気が済むまで
（火ノ丸）ウワッ！
No... But how?
ウソ…　なんで？　最初の１回は
まぐれだったってこと？
Was the first one a fluke?
Damn... I think I had the timing right there...
（火ノ丸）
くそ…　タイミングは完璧(かんぺき)なはず
（三尾錦）
もう一度 俺とやろうか？
Want to fight me again?
（火ノ丸）あっ…　三尾錦関
Mionishiki-zeki.
This is the same feeling I had with Hikage.
この感じ
日景のときにも感じたイヤな予感
The sinking feeling.
Ignore it!
かまうな！　いけ！
There!
（三尾錦）おらぁ！
そ… そんな…
N-No...
Even Mionishiki-zeki, who he threw earlier...
一度投げた三尾錦関にまで…
Now you know the truth
about your technique.
（三尾錦）これが この技の真実さ
確かに最初は めんくらったよ
見たこともない技だからね
You caught me unawares the first time, sure.
I'd never seen a technique like that before.
でも 特殊ゆえに もろさも十二分
But it has more than its
fair share of weaknesses.
日々 研究し 研究されてを
繰り返す俺たち関取には—
We sekitori spend our days
analyzing and being analyzed.
The same trick doesn't work on us twice.
２度は通用しないよ
Okay, looks like playtime's over.
さあ　お遊びは この辺にして
そろそろ稽古始めますか
Let's get back to training.
（関取たち）ウイッス
Yeah.
Having his move anticipated like
that must come as quite a shock.
（千鶴子）ショックですよね
いちばんの技を破られて
で… でもさ
相手はプロ中のプロなわけじゃない
Y-Yeah, but he's fighting
elite pro sumo wrestlers.
高校生が相手なら
こうは ならないはずよ
High schoolers wouldn't
be able to do that.
You may be right that only pros
would be able to counter a technique
確かに １度見せただけで
破られるなんて芸当は—
that they've only seen once.
プロにしかできないかもしれない
でも 映像に収められて
何度も見て研究されたら…
But if a move is recorded
and analyzed over and over...
It's entirely possible the same
thing could happen at nationals.
今日見た光景が 全国大会でも
再現される可能性は高いのでは…
My body and spirit have
reached their limits.
（火ノ丸）心も体も上限いっぱい
My trump card has been defeated.
残された技も打ち止め
Does this mean I can't get any stronger?
ワシは もう
これ以上 強くなれない？
So he really can't become a yokozuna.
やっぱムリじゃん 横綱なんて
I mean, his spirit, body and
technique have all peaked.
だって 心も体も技も 頭打ちで…
フン…　技が頭打ち？
His technique has peaked?
Technique is something you spend
your whole life developing.
技ってのはな 人生全てを費やして
探求するもんなんだ
There is no end point, young lady.
終わりなんてねえんだよ
お嬢ちゃん
アホか ワシは！　冴ノ山関に
言われたばっかじゃろうが！
I'm being stupid!
Remember what Saenoyama-zeki
said to you, you idiot!
Don't give up! Think!
くじけるな！　考えろ！
There must be something
I can learn from the ozeki here!
これから来る大関の強さに
学べるところがあるはず
Show me your face.
（駿海）ツラ見せな
（火ノ丸）あっ…　えっ？
You've got about as much life
in you as a worm, but that'll do.
虫の息だが 死んじゃいねえから
よしとしよう
Hasegawa!
長谷川(はせがわ)！
誰？　私の昔の しこ名で…
Who's calling me by my old moniker?
I'm going to borrow this little demon.
この小鬼 ちょっくら借りてくぞ
Thank you for your hard work!
（関取たち）
お疲れさんでございます！
You're all too loud.
（駿海）うるせえな
Why is that man here?
Is this Master Shibakiyama's doing?
どうして あの方が…
柴木山親方の差し金？
The sekitori are acting differently.
（千鶴子）関取衆の様子が…
（礼奈）あのじじい 何者？
Who exactly is that old geezer?
Go, Ushio-kun.
（冴ノ山）
行きなさい 潮君　いや 行くべきだ
I mean, you should go with him.
I'm actually rather envious of you.
正直 羨ましいですよ
私が行きたいくらいだ
I wish I could swap places with you.
Hey.
（駿海）おい　そこの娘も１人来い
One of you girls can come, too.
You.
お前　生意気そうな茶髪のほう
The sassy-looking brunette.
Huh? Who, me?
えっ？　私？
（火ノ丸）
あの…　ワシらは どこへ？
Um, where are we going?
Hey. Just who is this old coot?
ねえ
ホントに何なの？　あのじじい
Pardon me.
あの…　すみません
I'm not sure what you have in mind,
but I have very little time.
何だか分かりませんが
ワシには時間がありません
I was planning on staying in that
tent and training with the ozeki.
ワシは あの場所に残って
大関と相撲を…
We're here.
（駿海）ここだ
（２人）うん？
Jeez, look at this mansion!
（礼奈）
何よ この豪邸　ホントに何者？
Seriously, who are you?
開けろ
Open it.
There's dust everywhere!
（火ノ丸）ほこりが…
（せきこみ）
You want to train with the ozeki?
（駿海）大関とやりてえだって？
なにが大関だ
What's so great about them?
None of them are champions.
優勝したことも ねえくせに
If you insist, I'll let you decide.
そんなに言うんなら選ばせてやる
俺は優しいからな
I'm a nice guy, after all.
Would you rather go back
and train with the ozeki, or...
今すぐ帰って 大関と相撲を取るか
それとも…
Will you let me, a former
yokozuna, instruct you?
（駿海）ここで 元横綱の
俺の指導を受けるか　どっちだ？
A f-former yokozuna?
も… 元横綱…
I'm telling you I'll hone that
technique into a real weapon.
俺が その技を
本物の必殺にしてやるってんだよ
Idiot.
バカ野郎
Stamina Jiro
All-You-Can-Eat Barbecue
（小関）名古屋メシ うまいね！
（佑真）味噌が あと引くな
Nagoya cuisine tastes so good!
The miso is the real star.
I could eat this stuff forever!
（千比路）いっくらでも食えるな
（小関）うん！
Yeah!
Are those kids the ones
（厚木弟）確か こいつらは…
who brought my brother's restaurant
to its knees, the Dachi High sumo club?
兄さんのお店に大打撃を与えた
ダチ高相撲部の…
Older brother
Brother!
（厚木弟）兄さん！
Younger
Brother
This is my chance to avenge him!
今こそ
兄さんの無念を晴らすとき！
Hey, this is a miso cake!
これ 味噌ケーキだって
（厚木弟）今なら特別…
（小関）うん？
Here's the special miso topping
to go with it. On the house.
味噌トッピング
無料サービスだよ〜！
（小関）ウワッ！
これは さすがにムリ！
I can't eat that!
Next Bout  "100-yen-coin Training"